Flat 2, Canfield House, Finchley Road
London

© 07414988908

⊠ rmacg89@gmail.com

'® www.github.com/ryanmacg

Ryan MacGillivray

Summary

Description

Hi, I'm Ryan! I've spent since 2011 working, with Ruby, Ruby on Rails and the Rails stack in general. I like to poke at things and see how they work, give talks on things I know nothing about so I have to learn about them and make coffee in an obsessive manner.

When I'm not playing with Ruby, Go, or Swift I sometimes make beer which I then feed to my coworkers or arrange beer and bad movie nights in the office.

Computer Skills

Languages:

Fluent: Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Working Knowledge: JavaScript, PHP, Coffeescript, jQuery, ReactJS, Go, Python

Experience

2016 - present

Developer, Currency Cloud, London.

- o Worked as part of a team to deliver a new ReactJS checkout for Dulux
- Worked on new funtionality for Solidus API for the ReactJS checkout
- o Worked alongside team to develop internal product during company retreat
- o Communicating with clients and maintaining existing applications
- Mentoring of developer outwith company to learn JS

2015 - 2016

Developer, Currency Cloud, London.

- o Working on FinTech platform comprising of JRuby, Sinatra and Rails applications
- o Migration of Sinatra application off of HornetQ to RabbitMQ
- o Migration of Sinatra application off of Torquebox to modern application server

2013 - 2015

Ruby On Rails Developer, tictoc family, Glasgow.

- Lead developer on several larger client sites including SCO, B-Eat and GAP Group
- Lead developer on an as yet unreleased product:
 - Developed admin backend for product
 - Converted several costly actions to background jobs using Active Job, Sidekiq and the Services pattern
 - Established standard JSON format for several disparate APIs
 - Developed initial prototype and client facing implementation of project
- o Contributed to proprietary Rails 4 based CMS for use in client projects.

2011 - 2013

IT Support Technician, JTC Furniture Group, Dundee.

o Led development on two internal Ruby on Rails (3.2) based tools that have since been open sourced.

Education

2007 - 2011

Computing, University of Abertay, Dundee, Bachelor of Science.

Extra

- o Maintainer of Glub gem see https://github.com/ryanmacg/glub
- Built Kerstman secret santa matcher see https://github.com/ryanmacg/kerstman and https://kerstman.herokuapp.com/
- Delivered lightning talk at Scottish Ruby Users Group and LRUG on Postgres Arrays in Rails 4 see https://www.haikudeck.com/p/DJFtjsL98H/database-fuckery